Brno, Czech Republic 🏫

+420 792 303 303 📞

alex.buaiscia@gmail.com

Alex Buaiscia in

www.alexbuaiscia.com

# Alex Buaiscia

JS/React Web developer

Experienced application engineer working with APIs, DBs, webservers . Creating automation web apps using nodeJS / React to operate safe and easy deployments or to provide access to monitoring.

#### **Skills**

- HTML5 / CSS3
- Javascript / NodeJS
- React
- mongoDB / graphQL

- Git
- SQL
- Linux / Bash
- Weblogic / Apache

# **Web Projects**

2019

## **Portal Web Application**

Created for work purposes, the tool was made to make life easier to my team. It consists of an aggregation of tools used in daily working tasks into a single, easily accessible page, with a portal UI.

It passes props from functions in a class component from tree top to bottom stateless components. GraphQL is fetching data for the navbars.

I made it easier for the team to add additional tools by themselves using almost no code and setting up only a JS config file for an easy customization. The main component UI uses CSS grid.

This tool was created from a Gatsby starter and then heavily modified with ReactJS. It is deployed and served directly on an Apache server.

Portfolio with example demo here – Github repository here

2018

#### **Deployment Tool App**

I created this application to help my team do automatic deployments, making them safer and easier. Its functionalities:

- 1. Create an application backup, upload and deploy the package on the first server of the cluster and display logs.
- 2. Make a mockup sync on the second server of the cluster and then, when given parameters from the frontend, sync all the cluster and restart the required services.

The application relies on EJS for frontend and NodeJS / Express for backend. It is deployed on a Unix automation server and communicates with the application server through ssh.

Portfolio with example demo here – Github repository here

#### **Personal Website and Portfolio**

Constantly updated, the website is a partial show of my work with vanilla JS. It uses the EJS engine to integrate JS in HTML and it includes both frontend and backend.

The site is static, however, it is built with a backbone of NodeJS (with Express) for routing, auth, connection to DB, modelling, security; in the blog section the data is stored on mongoDB (which manages both users and authentication, among others).

Portfolio showcase and website here - Github repository here

# **Experience**

OCT 2016 - PRESENT

## **Application Support Engineer / EmbedIT, Brno (CZ)**

I'm in charge of deep level investigations of APIs errors / failures or other issues of various kinds; deployments; leading testing / making datafixes on DB level for test and Prod environments; managing the Weblogic servers.

Moreover, I'm making automation and monitoring tools or scripts with JS / Unix technologies. In July 2018 I was awarded the Extraordinary Achievements prize by EmbedIT, and my team received the Best Team prize by EmbedIT for the year 2018.

APR 2016 - SEP 2016

#### **Application Support Specialist L1.5 / EmbedIT, Brno (CZ)**

I was solving basic issues and running analysis through Oracle SQL in our DB. My main tasks were: investigation of API failures or errors using logs (Kibana Elastic Search) and DB; management of reports or escalations and tickets resolution; monitoring systems through Netcool / Nagios / Kibana dashboards; basic deployments.

OCT 2014 - MAR 2016

#### IT Help Desk / IBM, Brno (CZ)

I was in charge of emails and communication between customers and technical levels. I handled calls from customers, helped with problem determination, first troubleshooting, ticket management with backlogs, and severities.

## **Education**

SEP 2008 - AUG 2010

Master in Investigative Journalism / Associazione Giornalismo Investigativo (AGI), Milan (Italy)

#### **Extra-curricular activities**

I'm teaching people how to get to know themselves better and how to reach an inner state of well-being through meditation.

At this moment, I'm leading in-person courses in the city where I live.

In the past, I've done meditation and stress-management courses in companies.

Hobbies: studying languages and tech topics; reading about history and astronomy

#### Courses

NOV 2018

## Python 101 / KnowledgeHut

JUN 2019

## **Docker training / Seico**

OCT 2018

## ITIL Foundation / Tayllor & Cox

MAY 2017

## Weblogic server 12c: Administration I / Oracle University

## Languages

- Italian native
- English proficient, C1
- Spanish proficient, C1
- Czech lower-intermediate, A2/B1